so let's look at our solution
when we have a problem like this we
first figure out the dependencies there
is one from here to here and another one
from here to here and there is also
dependence here from r7 to r7 so now
let's look at our ilp so for ilp we can
do this and this in the first cycle they
don't depend on anything this one needs
to be done in the second cycle because
it depends on the first two instructions
this one however can be done in the
first cycle this one cannot it needs the
r7 that is produced by this one
so this gets done in the second cycle
and then this one actually doesn't
depend on anything so it can also be
done in the first cycle so as far as ilp
is concerned we have
a total of six instructions executed
over two cycles so the ilp is going to
be three for the ipc we have to worry
not only about these dependencies but
also
that this is a three issue processor and
that it's in order
so this can still be done in the first
cycle
this can be done in the first cycle as
far as three issue is concerned this
could be done in the first cycle but
because it has a dependence we still
have to delay it by one cycle and now
the problem is that in an inorder
processor once we don't execute an
instruction we cannot execute
instructions past it because that would
be out of order so this is all that
happens in the first cycle in this
processor
in the second cycle we are able to
execute this instruction because now the
first two are done
we can execute this one
because now that this one is done this
is eligible for execution and then we
have to stop here because of this
dependence so this would have to be done
in the third cycle and again we cannot
do this so in the last third cycle we
will be able to finally do this and then
this because they don't depend on each
other so they can be done in the same
cycle so now we have
six instructions over three cycles
for an ipc of
two
it turns out that even if this was a two
issue processor the inorder property
really would still limit us to a ipc of
two so sometimes one of the things is
going to be in limitations sometimes
another limitation is going to play a
dominant role sometimes all of the
limitations are going to play a role in
limiting our ipc